Yessenia Chaiu Zhang

Oakland, CA | ychaiu@gmail.com | (415) 271-8448 | https://github.com/ychaiu

TECHNOLOGIES

Languages | Python, JavaScript, SQL, HTML, CSS, SQL

Database/Industry Tools | React, Redux, Flask, SQLAlchemy, Pandas, PostgreSQL, Git, Command Line **Software** | ArcMap, ArcGIS Pro, ArcPy, QGIS, Google Earth, Google Suite, Microsoft Office Suite

PROJECTS

HAZMAP

A single-page web app for reporting environmental hazards, built using React/Redux. On a map generated from the Google Maps API, users can explore reports, create markers, and upload information and photos. Photo upload and storage is handled by the Cloudinary API. Report data is served and queried on the backend by PostgreSQL, SQLAlchemy, and Flask. Github: https://github.com/ychaiu/env-haz-app

Industry Projects

- Use spatial analysis libraries, including, ArcPy, GeoPandas, and Pysal, to automate geoprocessing operations and to perform complex geographical analysis
- Scripting in Python to facilitate internal workflows, such as QA/QC, data format conversions, and data downloads
- Database management of the 60K+ parks in the California Protected Areas Database in PostgreSQL. Responsibilities include data modeling, form validation, schema re-ordering, and data querying and export

WORK EXPERIENCE

GreenInfo Network, Oakland, CA

Web Developer

• In-house transition to a web developer role, working on interactive mapping projects. Technology stack will include Django, React, Javascript, AWS, and Heroku

Geospatial Analyst

Nov 2016 - Present

Mar 2019 - Present

- Processed and analyzed large geospatial datasets for visualization in web and print maps
- Lead geographical analysis for various projects, including Bay Area Greenprint and Community Water Center Drinking Vulnerability Tool
- Analyzed park access in CA using buffer tools, proportional analysis, and weighted averages
- Aggregated US census data at different geography levels and generated demographic summaries

San Francisco Department of Public Health, San Francisco, CA

Patient Services Coordinator

Aug 2015 - Nov 2016

- Served as community liaison between the SF Health Network clinics and the San Francisco patient population
- Interpreted health information and coordinated primary care for culturally diverse communities

UCLA Department of Epidemiology, Los Angeles, CA

Assistant Public Administrative Analyst

Nov 2012 - Jun 2014

• Managed a state-wide Parkinson's Disease patient database by communicating with healthcare providers, compiling patients into the registry, and collecting and cleaning the subsequent data in Microsoft Access

EDUCATION

Hackbright Academy, San Francisco, CA

Sep 2018 - Feb 2019

Software Engineering Program

Accelerated 6 month, full-stack software engineering program for women. Technology stack includes Python, Flask, React/Redux, HTML/CSS, PostgreSQL, Jinja.

Penn State, Remote Jan 2016 - Nov 2016

Geographic Information Systems (GIS) Certificate - GIS database development, GIS automation and programming

University of California, Los Angeles, Los Angeles, CA

Master of Public Health, Environmental Health Bachelor of Science, Environmental Sciences June 2015